Guide to the New York University Collection of Contemporary Composers' Websites MSS.496
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Shin, Myungsoo, February 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions and projects, news relating to Shin and his works, a catalogue of his music, and examples of his music in the form of embedded audio and video files. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work as a composer of instrumental music for the stage, television, and live performance. His pieces make use of classical, jazz, contemporary, electronic, and world music techniques and styles. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the December 2017 capture of the site.
- Siegel, Aaron, February 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://aaronsiegel.net in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded youtube and Soundcloud audio files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions and projects, a calendar of his events, press relating to Siegel and his works, and examples of his music in the form of embedded audio and video files. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work as a composer of music for percussion instruments and ensembles, as well as operas. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the January 2018 capture of the site.
- Sierra, Arlene, November 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.arlenesierra.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded Flash player audio files on the site were not captured due to technological constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about her compositions and projects, a calendar of her events, a catalog of her works, press and news relating to the artist and her compositions, a gallery of images of the artist, a discography of her published albums, news, interviews, and reviews relating to Sierra, and examples of her works in the form of embedded audio and video files. The compositions featured on the site highlight her work as a composer of classically-influenced instrumental music, primarily for orchestral and small or large ensemble performance. Capture of the site began in November 2017. This description is based on the November 2017 capture of the site.
- Smith, Wadada Leo, November 2017- ongoing; Wadada Leo Smith's Golden Quartet; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.wadadaleosmith.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions and projects, examples of his prose works, a discography of his published albums, a gallery of images of the artist and his performances, and press and news relating to Smith. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work as a trumpet player and composer of jazz and blues influenced music, and his participation in a variety of musical ensembles. Capture of the site began in November 2017. This description is based on the November 2017 capture of the site.
  Wadada Leo Smith's Silver Orchestra; Wadada Leo Smith's Organic (Musical group); Wadada Leo Smith's Golden Quintet; Wadada Leo Smith's Golden Quartet
- Smooke, David, August 2016- ongoing; cuid5895; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.davidsmooke.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, a list of his works, news related to his work, audio files and videos, photos, and an online store. Smooke's performances reflect years working in theater as a director, producer and stagehand. He performs improvisations and original pieces on several instruments. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the May 2017 capture of the site.
- Snider, Sarah Kirkland, February 2014- ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://sarahkirklandsnider.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded image files, audio, and Soundcloud audio files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about her compositions and projects, news and press relating to Snider, a calendar of her events, and examples of her work in the form of embedded audio and video files. The compositions featured on the site highlight her work as a composer of contemporary classical music for orchestras, ensembles, and soloists. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the December 2017 capture of the site.
  Also includes the interactive github website of a movement of Sarah Kirkland Snider's Mass for the Endangered, on the subject of endangered animals and the climate crisis.
- Snowden, Steven, February 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.stevensnowden.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded Youtube and Vimeo video files and Soundcloud audio files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions and projects, a discography of his published albums, examples of Snowden's work in the form of embedded audio and video files, and a calendar of his events. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work as a composer of bluegrass, folk, and rock influenced instrumental music for dance, theater, installations, and concert performance. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the November 2017 capture of the site.
- Snyder, Jeff, February 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.scattershot.org/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions and projects, his CV, a discography of his published albums, and examples of his works in the form of embedded audio and video files. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work as a composer of improvisational and notated music making use of the electronic instruments he designs and builds as well as traditional instruments. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the November 2017 capture of the site.
- Sokolović, Ana, February 2015-ongoing
  Website for the Quebec-based composer Ana Sokolović. Includes a biography and headshots, news and calendar of events, press on her compositions, a discography, and a catalogue of instrumental, vocal, opera, and incidental works.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.anasokolovic.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
- SoundArt Foundation, May 2017; cuid5858; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.soundart.org/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website details the composers supported and promoted by the Foundation. It contains a list of supported musicians, information about each, and a calendar of the artists' events. Capture of the website began in May 2017. This description is based on the May 2017 capture of the site.
- Southworth, Christine, April 2014-ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived websites.
  Christine Southworth (b. 1978) is a composer and video artist based in Lexington, Massachusetts. Her music incorporates natural and man/machine-made sound. The website contains compositions for string quartets, standard and non-standard ensembles, gamelan, and electronic; videos of performances; music videos; art; photography; and performance listings. The URL changed in 2021.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of christinesouthworth.com and kotekan.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
- Spiegel, Laurie, February 2015- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://retiary.org/ls/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about her compositions and projects, interviews with and press about her, and examples of Spiegel's work in the form of prose writings and visual art. The compositions featured on the site highlight her work as a performer and composer of multi-instrumental acoustic, electronic, and computer music. Capture of the site began in February 2015. This description is based on the October 2017 capture of the site.
- Steiger, Rand, February 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://rand.info/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions and projects, a discography of his published albums, press and news relating to Steiger and his works, downloadable versions of his scores and essays, and examples of his music in the form of embedded audio and video files. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work as a conductor and composer of pieces using traditional instruments and computer music for orchestral and ensemble performance. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the December 2017 capture of the site.
- Stone, Carl, April 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.sukothai.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded Soundcloud audio files on the site were not captured due to technological constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions and projects, news and reviews about Stone, a discography of his published albums, a gallery of images of the artist, a calendar of his events, and examples of his works in the form of embedded audio files. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work as a composer of live computer music that makes extensive use of sampling. Capture of the site began in April 2014. This description is based on the November 2017 capture of the site.
- Streber, Ryan, August 2015-July 2020; cuid5863; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://ryanstreber.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, a list of his works, information on his recording studio, and contact information. Streber composes concert music, scored two short films, designed sound for several theatrical productions, and collaborated with other artists on pop, rock, experimental, and jazz compositions. Capture of the site began in August 2015. This description is based on the May 2017 capture of the site.
- Talbot, Joby, April 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://jobytalbot.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded image and Issuu files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played. Embedded Squarespace audio files were not captured due to technological constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions and projects, excerpts of reviews of his works, a calendar of his events, and examples of Talbot's work in the form of embedded audio file. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work as a composer of classically-influenced instrumental and choral music in a variety of genres for concert, film, and stage performance. Capture of the site began in April 2014. This description is based on the October 2017 capture of the site.
- Tao, Conrad, November 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://conradtao.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions and projects, excerpts of reviews of his works, a calendar of his events, a discography of his published albums, a gallery of images of the artist, and examples of Tao's work in the form of embedded video files. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work as a pianist and composer of classically-influenced instrumental music using traditional and electronic instruments for orchestral and chamber performance, as well as solo pieces. Capture of the site began in November 2017. This description is based on the November 2017 capture of the site.
- Thomas, Augusta Read, April 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.augustareadthomas.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about her compositions and projects, press relating to Thomas, a calendar of her events, and examples of her work in the form of embedded audio and video files. The compositions featured on the site highlight her work as a composer of classically influenced instrumental music for orchestral, solo, and chamber performance. Capture of the site began in April 2014. This description is based on the December 2017 capture of the site.
- Thomas, David Evan, April 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.davidevanthomas.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded images and audio files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions, awards, commission policy, and projects, a discography of his published albums, press and interviews relating to Thomas, a calendar of his events, his blog, and examples of his works in the form of embedded audio files. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work as a composer of instrumental and vocal music for large and small ensembles. Genres of his works include opera, orchestral, wind ensemble, chamber, keyboard, and choral. Capture of the site began in April 2014. This description is based on the November 2017 capture of the site.
- Thomson, Ken, February 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://ktonline.net/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded audio files and Youtube video files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions and projects, a discography of his published albums, press and news relating to Thomson and his works, and examples of his music in the form of embedded audio and video files. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work as a saxophonist, clarinetist, and composer of instrumental music that makes use of jazz, punk-rock, and new music styles. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the December 2017 capture of the site.
- Torke, Michael, February 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.michaeltorke.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions and projects, excerpts of reviews of his works, a gallery of images of the artist, and examples of Torke's work in the form of embedded audio files. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work as a pianist and composer of classically-influenced instrumental music for small and large ensemble performance. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the July 2017 capture of the site.
- Trapani, Christopher, February 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://christophertrapani.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions and projects, press and news relating to Trapani and his works, a catalogue and discography of his music, a calendar of his events, and examples of his music in the form of embedded audio and video files. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work as a conductor and composer of instrumental pieces for a variety of instruments, both electric and acoustic. Many of his works are microtonal. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the December 2017 capture of the site.
- Twining, Toby, November 2017; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of https://tobytwiningmusic.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded images, Soundcloud audio, and Youtube videos on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
  The site is defunct as of December 2017, and no further accruals will occur.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions and projects, excerpts of reviews of his works, and examples of Twining's work in the form of embedded audio files. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work a composer of rock and jazz inspired vocal and instrumental experimental music. He is also the leader of the group Toby Twining Music, a small vocal ensemble. Capture of the site began in November 2017. This description is based on the November 2017 capture of the site.
  Toby Twining Music
- Urie, Nicholas, November 2015- ongoing; cuid5942; 3 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://nicholasurie.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, a list of his works, press articles, photo gallery, online store, and contact information. Urie led large jazz ensembles and full symphony orchestras performing works that range from jazz to contemporary classical music. Capture of the site began in February 2015. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- Vasiliki, Krimitza, September 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of https://krimitzavasiliki.wordpress.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Images and Google Drive files were not captured due to technological constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about her compositions and projects, excerpts of reviews of her works, and examples of Vasiliki's work in the form of embedded audio files. The compositions featured on the site highlight her work a composer of classically-influenced instrumental music for large and small ensemble performance. Capture of the site began in September 2017. This description is based on the September 2017 capture of the site.
- Vierk, Lois V., November 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://loisvvierk.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about her compositions and projects, excerpts of reviews of her works, scores for her compositions, and interviews with Vierk. The compositions featured on the site highlight her work a composer of Japanese and classically influenced instrumental music for performance by soloists and large and small ensembles. The site also notes her participation in the musical group Go Guitars. Capture of the site began in November 2017. This description is based on the November 2017 capture of the site.
  Go Guitars (Musical group)
- Viñao, Ezequiel, November 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.tloneditions.com/ezequiel_vinao.html in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions and projects, excerpts of reviews of his works, scores for his compositions, interviews with Viñao, a discography of his published albums, and examples of his works in the form of embedded audio and video files. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work as a pianist and composer of pieces influenced by the music of India and making use of traditional and electronic instruments. Capture of the site began in November 2017. This description is based on the November 2017 capture of the site.
- Vincent, Jonathan, February 2015-ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived websites.
  Jonathan Vincent is a composer, sound designer, producer and arranger for television, film and other media. The website contains production and arrangement work, news, videos containing his music, music credits, and Bandcamp music players.